<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on 127.0.0.1</title><link>https://127001.me/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on 127.0.0.1</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Dmytro Kostiuchenko</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 01:52:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://127001.me/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How do you change browser in Slack anyway?</title><link>https://127001.me/post/change-browser-in-slack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 01:52:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://127001.me/post/change-browser-in-slack/</guid><description>&lt;p>Overriding the default browser in Slack is my vexatious personal itch. I have a dedicated browser just for work, and I use Slack solely for work. Any link from Slack, be it a GitHub pull request, an unlisted corporate video on YouTube, or an internal meme, I want to open it in my work-only browser. Everything else I want to open in my default browser. &lt;em>And if I get this to work, I’ll be awesome&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, you may argue: but hey, why would you mix your work and personal environments? That’s not healthy! Get yourself a different laptop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow, dear, wow! What discipline and work ethics you have. &lt;em>Let’s go. In and out, twenty-minute adventure&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="image-block">&lt;img src="https://127001.me/post/change-browser-in-slack/
img/rick_morty_in_out.jpg" alt="rick morty in out"/>&lt;/div>
&lt;small style="color: grey;">Rick &amp;amp; Morty. Season 3, Episode 6. TM &amp;amp; © Adult Swim&lt;/small></description></item><item><title>Ten years of ThinkPadding</title><link>https://127001.me/post/ten-years-of-thinkpadding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 02:30:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://127001.me/post/ten-years-of-thinkpadding/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m the author of the title picture, and these are my ThinkPads. I’ve been very loyal to the ThinkPad brand for more than a decade. Until Lenovo sold me a lemon — ThinkPad X13 AMD. That event encouraged me to reflect on my loyalty. Which I did, and now I’m happy to share the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How did I reflect? I looked at the ThinkPad evolution under Lenovo by comparing all the models I own: X220, X270 and X13 AMD (and occasionally a very similar T14s). If there was something I liked in X220 which Lenovo killed in subsequent models, I put it on &lt;em>the bad&lt;/em> list. If there is something that Lenovo kept or even improved in its newer models, I put it on &lt;em>the good&lt;/em> list. By doing so, I was hoping to understand if my loyalty to ThinkPads still has any rational grounds or is mainly driven by habit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, as a bonus, I will share what’s so awful about X13 AMD (and any other AMD-based laptop sold by Lenovo).&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="admonition-block caution" role="doc-notice">&lt;h6 class="block-title">&lt;span class="title-label">Caution: &lt;/span>Biases ahead 😉&lt;/h6>&lt;p>When I started working on this post, I did not know where my reflecting would lead me. I admit that I had a feeling I was going to bash Lenovo for selling me a terrible product, but nevertheless, I tried to remain calm and rational. Despite my trying, you may find some statements biased and unjustified&lt;/p>&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>Eliminate backlight flicker with Intel i915</title><link>https://127001.me/post/eliminate-backlight-flicker-with-i915/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 22:30:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://127001.me/post/eliminate-backlight-flicker-with-i915/</guid><description>&lt;aside class="admonition-block note" role="note">&lt;h6 class="block-title label-only">&lt;span class="title-label">Note: &lt;/span>&lt;/h6>&lt;p>This is a revised version of my post from 2013 previously published at
&lt;a class="bare" href="http://devbraindom.blogspot.com/2013/03/eliminate-led-screen-flicker-with-intel.html">http://devbraindom.blogspot.com/2013/03/eliminate-led-screen-flicker-with-intel.html&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although still popular, that post was full of factual mistakes.&lt;/p>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>The brightness of LED backlight in TFT displays is sometimes controlled using a technique called PWM or &lt;em>pulse width
modulation&lt;/em>. If implemented incorrectly, particularly if PWM frequency is too low, it can introduce distracting visual
effects and induce eye strain, headaches, and even dizziness in some
people&lt;a class="footnote-ref" id="_footnoteref_1" href="#_footnote_1" title="View footnote 1" role="doc-noteref">[1]&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many older laptops set PWM frequency for their backlight too low. Luckily, in laptops equipped with Intel i915 GPU the
PWM frequency is often controlled by the GPU and thus can be adjusted by a software.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turning Synology NAS into a geeky media server: PulseAudio</title><link>https://127001.me/post/synology/mediaserver-p2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://127001.me/post/synology/mediaserver-p2/</guid><description>&lt;section class="admonition-block warning" role="doc-notice">&lt;h6 class="block-title label-only">&lt;span class="title-label">Warning: &lt;/span>&lt;/h6>&lt;p>This post was written in pre-docker era. Back in the time it was necessary to perform many things that are
no longer required on modern devices (like installing Debian Chroot package which, expectedly, is no longer offered).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Modern devices with Docker support or equivalent features (FWIW, my choice is Linux Station from QNAP) are much more
friendly towards linux enthusiasts&lt;/p>&lt;/section>
&lt;aside class="admonition-block note" role="note">&lt;h6 class="block-title label-only">&lt;span class="title-label">Note: &lt;/span>&lt;/h6>&lt;p>Required files can be downloaded from &lt;a class="bare" href="https://github.com/edio/synology-mediaserver">https://github.com/edio/synology-mediaserver&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://127001.me/post/synology/mediaserver-p1">Previously&lt;/a> we’ve covered ALSA setup and Debian chroot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post I’ll describe how to set up PulseAudio in Debian chroot, so that it’s possible to stream any sound from
linux-powered pc to a sound card connected to Synology NAS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turning Synology NAS into a geeky media server</title><link>https://127001.me/post/synology/mediaserver-p1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 01:51:40 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://127001.me/post/synology/mediaserver-p1/</guid><description>&lt;section class="admonition-block warning" role="doc-notice">&lt;h6 class="block-title label-only">&lt;span class="title-label">Warning: &lt;/span>&lt;/h6>&lt;p>This post was written in pre-docker era. Back in the time it was necessary to perform many things that are
no longer required on modern devices (like installing Debian Chroot package which, expectedly, is no longer offered).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Modern devices with Docker support or equivalent features (FWIW, my choice is Linux Station from QNAP) are much more
friendly towards linux enthusiasts&lt;/p>&lt;/section>
&lt;aside class="admonition-block note" role="note">&lt;h6 class="block-title label-only">&lt;span class="title-label">Note: &lt;/span>&lt;/h6>&lt;p>Required files can be downloaded from &lt;a class="bare" href="https://github.com/edio/synology-mediaserver">https://github.com/edio/synology-mediaserver&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>I’m not a huge fan of Synology. I bought my DS214 by friend’s recommendation and became frustrated with it right after
the purchase. Bundled software was limited and buggy. Many people find Synology products great. But for me it just
didn’t work well because it forced its use cases on me instead of being a helpful tool for my own very specific use
cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, I wasn’t willing to lose money on reselling my NAS, so I decided to get as much as possible from it and
currently with my DS214Play I can:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="olist arabic">&lt;ol class="arabic">&lt;li>Play virtually any sound via connected USB sound card.&lt;/li>&lt;li>Particularly, I can play my huge collection of high-resolution music in various formats (with replaygain tags
respected). All that thanks to &lt;em>mpd&lt;/em>, which I can control from any decent phone, web-browser or even smart-watch and
scrobble all statistics to Last.fm.&lt;/li>&lt;li>Stream sound from my laptop via &lt;strong>PulseAudio&lt;/strong>, while watching videos on YouTube or movies.&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>randrctl — profile-based screen manager for X</title><link>https://127001.me/post/introducing-randrctl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 18:45:22 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://127001.me/post/introducing-randrctl/</guid><description>&lt;p>While having some free time, decided to automate one of my daily routines — setting up external display.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Idea appeared long before I was told about famous (or not?) &lt;a href="https://github.com/wertarbyte/autorandr">autorandr&lt;/a> project.
So if you are familiar with autorandr, you are already familiar with randrctl idea.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>