<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thinkpad on 127.0.0.1</title><link>https://127001.me/tags/thinkpad/</link><description>Recent content in thinkpad on 127.0.0.1</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Dmytro Kostiuchenko</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 02:30:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://127001.me/tags/thinkpad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ten years of ThinkPadding</title><link>https://127001.me/post/ten-years-of-thinkpadding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 02:30:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://127001.me/post/ten-years-of-thinkpadding/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m the author of the title picture, and these are my ThinkPads. I’ve been very loyal to the ThinkPad brand for more than a decade. Until Lenovo sold me a lemon — ThinkPad X13 AMD. That event encouraged me to reflect on my loyalty. Which I did, and now I’m happy to share the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How did I reflect? I looked at the ThinkPad evolution under Lenovo by comparing all the models I own: X220, X270 and X13 AMD (and occasionally a very similar T14s). If there was something I liked in X220 which Lenovo killed in subsequent models, I put it on &lt;em>the bad&lt;/em> list. If there is something that Lenovo kept or even improved in its newer models, I put it on &lt;em>the good&lt;/em> list. By doing so, I was hoping to understand if my loyalty to ThinkPads still has any rational grounds or is mainly driven by habit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, as a bonus, I will share what’s so awful about X13 AMD (and any other AMD-based laptop sold by Lenovo).&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="admonition-block caution" role="doc-notice">&lt;h6 class="block-title">&lt;span class="title-label">Caution: &lt;/span>Biases ahead 😉&lt;/h6>&lt;p>When I started working on this post, I did not know where my reflecting would lead me. I admit that I had a feeling I was going to bash Lenovo for selling me a terrible product, but nevertheless, I tried to remain calm and rational. Despite my trying, you may find some statements biased and unjustified&lt;/p>&lt;/section></description></item></channel></rss>